We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
終わりなき旅の途中　立ち止まりそうな時
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
深いため息こぼす　僕らは
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
掴みかけてはまた離れていった
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
でも今はもう何も恐れることはない
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
心を繋ぐ強い絆は
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
けして解けはしないさ
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
探し続けて辿り着いた
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
この場所で Period に
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
悲しみ怒り 力に変えて
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
運命はすぐそばに
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
It's been a while, Al.
久しぶりだな  アル
Yeah.
So... I heard from Pinako.
その…ピナコから聞いたよ
About what happened to your body and such.
体のこととか
There he is!
いたいた
Mr. Hoh, do you think you could lend us a hand?
ホーさん  ちょっと手を貸してくれないか
Oh, sure.
はい
Let's catch up on things later.
じゃあ  あとでゆっくりな
S-Sure.
That radio you guys fixed for me back then has been working great.
あんたたちが直してくれたあのラジオ
あれから  調子いいよ
There's no static coming from it anymore.
雑音も入らなくなったし
I'm sorry. All of this happened because we messed with Cornello.
ごめんなさい
僕たちがコーネロに
ちょっかい出したばっかりに…
Hey, don't worry about it.
気にすんな
The city came to its senses because you two exposed his crime.
不正を暴いてくれたお陰で
町は正気を取り戻した
I guess there was a riot, but look at it now.
暴動やなんかもあったが
今は  ほら
Aren't those beautiful sounds?
いい音だろう
They're rebuilding the city.
町を挙げて
復興に取り組んでいるんだ
Leaving no resentment behind.
わだかまりを捨ててな
I'll go help out too.
僕も行ってくる
Please look after Winry for me, Rose.
ロゼ  ウィンリィをお願い
I guess we'll see what we can help out with.
どれ  オレたちも手伝うか
Let's go, Yoki.
行くぞ  ヨキ
Huh?
What about food?
飯は
It'll taste better if you eat after  you work!
働いて食った方がうまいだろ
おら  来い
Let's go!
Hey! Let go of me!
放せって
I want to eat!
飯～
Huh? That was your son?
さっきの息子さん
Oh, that must have been awfully rude of us.
あら  悪かったかしら
It must have been a while since you've seen him.
Can you really just leave him hanging?
久しぶりなんじゃない
ほっといていいの
Well, I left the house many years ago.
いや～
何年も前に家を出ちゃったんで
I don't think he trusts me as a father.
父親として信用されてないだろうし
Not really sure what to talk about with him...
何を話せばいいのやら…
父さ～ん
Dad!
Umm...
あの…僕も働く
I'll help too!
Let me take that for you.
それ  運びます
Here.
はい
How's the bath, Winry?
ウィンリィさん
湯加減はどうかしら
It's the best!
最高です
I don't even remember the last time I soaked in the tub...
湯ぶねにつかったのっていつ以来だろ
I'll leave your change of clothes right here.
着替えここに置いとくわね
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます
Rose's so sweet!
ロゼさん  いい人だ
I find you really admirable, by the way.
それにしても偉いわね
You're so young, but you've already set yourself up in the automail business.
その若さで機械鎧職人として
自立してるなんて
Did you make Ed's leg too?
エドの足もあなたが
Yeah.
We're old friends, so it was the least I could do.
幼なじみのよしみっていうか…
That's amazing!
すごいな～
エドが立ち上がるための足を作った人か
So you're the one who gave Ed a leg so he could stand up.
Then in turn, he gave me the strength to stand up.
回りまわって  私を
立ち上がらせてくれたんだから
So in a way, you saved me as well.
ウィンリィさんは
私の恩人でもあるわね
I was told my late boyfriend could be revived.
死んだ恋人を生き返らせてくれる…
Hearing that and believing in their miracles, I gave myself up to Leto.
奇跡の業というのを信じて
私はレト教にのめり込んでしまったの
That was just around the time when Ed and Al came here and exposed the priest's lies.
そんなときよ
エドとアルがこの町に来て
教主のペテンを暴露したのは
What I've been clinging on to just disappeared like that, so I was feeling pretty hopeless.
今まですがってきたものが
突然消えて  絶望したわ
And that was when Ed scolded me.
そしたら  エドに怒られちゃった
He told me to get up and keep on going.
自分の足で立って歩けって
I'm so sorry! He's always like that!
ごめんなさい
あいつ  いつもそうなんです
Why can't he be nicer about things?
なんで  もうちょっと
優しくなれないのかな～
It was  nice.
優しかったわ
That was Ed's kindness.
あれがエドの優しさ
You're aware of that too, aren't you?
あなたも分かってるんでしょ
Thanks to him, we came to our senses.
お陰で目が覚めた
Everyone in this city, including myself.
私もこの町も
We're all trying to get back on our feet without relying on miracles.
奇跡なんかに頼らず
みんな  自分の力で
立ち直ろうとしている
It's all thanks to Ed and Al.
エドとアルのお陰よ
Ed...
エド…
I followed those soldiers, but I ended up in some crazy place.
軍のヤツらに
くっついてきたはいいけど
なんだか とんでもない所に
迷い込んじまったなぁ
Mr. Greed...
グリードさん…
What is and is not ethical changes with time and also depends on whom you ask.
倫理などというものは
時代や個人によって変わるものだ
That is not the reason.
理由はそんなものではない
It is to prevent an individual from creating a powerful army of their own, Major General.
個人が強力な軍隊を
持たぬようにするためだよ  少将
They're not actually human...
人ではない…
人形ですか
They're dolls, I take it?
Precisely.
そうだ
We will create soldiers by inserting souls into these humanoids.
人の形をした入れ物に
魂を定着させ  兵をつくる
They will be the ultimate soldiers that obey our every command.
我々の命令のままに戦う最高の兵
In other words, an immortal army.
いわば  不死の軍団だ
Do you mind if I ask something?
質問してもよろしいでしょうか
What is it?
なんだね
Where would you obtain the souls to attach to them?
その定着させる魂とやらは
どこから調達するのですか
From the people of the countries we've crushed, and have yet to crush.
我々が踏みにじった…あるいは
これから踏みにじる
国の者たちからだ
The battlefield will become a hunting ground where we can obtain thousands of souls.
戦場は大量の魂を手に入れる
猟場となるのだよ
Central is scary!!
セントラル  怖ぇ  ひでぇ
It's unbelievably cruel!
どんでもねぇ
There's no way Mr. Greed would be here!
こんな所にグリードさんがいるわけねぇ
An underground tunnel?
地下トンネル
Yeah.
I wanted to check whether there's one under this city.
この町の地下にあるか確認したいんだ
If there is...!
もしあったら…
No, there has to be! Then-
いや  きっとある それを…
Hold that thought.
ちょっと待て
Let's take this somewhere private.
人目のない所へ行こう
So you came to Lior to prevent the activation of the Nationwide Transmutation Circle?
つまり  国土錬成陣の
発動を阻止するためにリオールに
Yeah.
Then I found you  here! What a surprise!
そしたら父さんがいてびっくりしたよ
It makes me feel lucky.
と同時にラッキーだとも
We met a man who looks just like you underneath Central.
セントラルの地下で
父さんそっくりな男を見たんだ
I seriously doubt that there's no link between you two.
父さんと無関係だとは思えない
I figured you knew who he was.
あいつが何者か
知ってるんじゃないかって
Are you sure this is a good idea, Alphonse?
いいのか  アルフォンス
What if I was on their side?
オレがあっち側の人間だったらどうする
Didn't you consider the possibility that everything you just said could make it to the enemy's ears?
こんなにしゃべって
筒抜けになるとは
考えなかったのか
I'm really happy that you trust me.
オレを信用してくれて
ありがとうな うれしいよ
Thanks.
Of course!
So he's trusting a failure like me as a real father...
こんな男でも一応父親とみて
信じてくれてんのかねぇ
Now...
さて…
I guess it's my  turn to trust my sons and to tell them everything I know.
オレも息子たちを信じてすべて話すか
It's a long story.
話せば  長くなるな
I want Edward to hear it as well.
エドワードにも聞いてもらいたいんだが
The thing is, Brother...
実は兄さん…
...has gone missing.
行方不明なんだ
Can I help the next customer, please?
次の方  どうぞ
I'd like to make a withdrawal from State Alchemist Edward Elric's research account.
国家錬金術師
エドワード·エルリックの
研究費口座から
金を引き出したい
Would that be you?
ご本人様ですか
No, I'm here on his behalf.
代理の者だ  委任状と署名もある
I have a power of attorney and also his signature.
Thank you, sir.
ありがとうございました
This is the northern branch of Banks Bank.
バンクス銀行  北区支店です
A withdrawal has just been made from
State Alchemist Mr. Edward Elric's account.
国家錬金術師
エドワード·エルリック氏の口座から
現金の引き出しがありました
The man claimed to be here on his behalf.
代理人だという男が
Yes. He was a very large man...
特徴は屈強な大男で…
Here's your money.
ほらよ  治療費だ
Okay. This should do.
はい  確かに頂きましたよ
Jesus, what a rip-off.
ったく
こんなにぼったくりやがって
What are you talking about?
何  言ってんだい
口止め料も含めりゃ妥当だろ
With the hush money included, this is just the right amount.
Well, we appreciate your not probing into our matters.
まあ  オレたちのことを
詮索しないでいてくれるのは
助かるがな
Darius!
ダリウス
They caught up to us.
気づかれたか
Coming.
はいはい
Oh my, a soldier.
おや  軍人さん  どこか悪いので
Is someone injured?
We're looking for someone.
人を捜している
Is he your only patient?
患者は一人だけか
Anyone staying in the back?
入院してる者は
Just one in the back-
奥にもう一人…
Are you the only one staying here?
入院患者はお前だけか
Yes... can I help you?
はあ  そうですが  何か
You're the one who went to the bank, aren't you?
貴様  銀行にいた男だな
Don't move!
動くな
Halt!
止まれ  この病院の者か
Are you from this clinic?
Both hands in the air, slowly!
布団から  ゆっくりと両手を出せ
Have you seen anyone going in and out of this clinic recently?
最近  この病院に出入りしている
よそ者を見なかったか
His characteristics are...
特徴は…
What's wrong?!
どうした  両手を上げろ
Both hands in the air!
Red coat, blonde hair in a braid...
赤いコートで金髪の三つ編みの…
...and very short.
チビ
What was that?!
なんだ
Harris!
ハリス
Get yourself together!
しっかりしろ  誰にやられた
Who did this to you?!
Hey Harri-
ハリ…
Cohen! Harris!
コーエン  ハリス
What happened?! Say something!
何があった  返事をしろ
Didn't bother to save any for us.
全部一人でやっちまいやがって
Don't push yourself.
あんまり無理すんな
You haven't fully recovered yet, have you?
まだ体力が戻ってないだろ
Don't treat me like a patient!
病人扱いすんな
I'm at full throttle and ready to go!
もう  バリンバリンの本調子全開だぜ
世話になったな  先生
Thanks for everything, Doc.
No need to thank me. Just go already!
礼はいいから  早く行きなさい
これ以上の面倒はごめんだよ
Try not to trouble us any further.
赤コート  三つ編みで捜索されてんのか
So they're looking for a blonde guy in a red coat who has his hair in a braid...
Maybe I'll stay like this for a while.
しばらくこの格好でいるのがよさそうだな
動くな
Freeze!
Put down your weapons!
武器を捨てろ
新手か
There's more of them?!
手を頭の上に  早くしろ
Hands above your head! Now!
そこの君
You!
危ないから離れて
Get away from those two! They're dangerous!
そっちこそ動くな
You're  the one that's going to freeze!
このガキの頭ふっ飛ばされたいか
You want to see this kid's head get blown off?!
足を確保するぞ
We're going to secure a vehicle.
Right.
ゴリさん  追っ手だ
They're after us, Donkey Kong!
Don't call me that!
ゴリ言うな
追いつかれちまうぞ
They're catching up!
They're from the northern army!
あいつら  北方軍だ
雪道じゃ勝てねぇ
I can't outrun them in the snow.
危なかったな
That was close.
How's it looking like in the back?
どうだ  後ろは
Bad! They're catching up!
ダメだ  追いつかれる
くそっ
Dammit...!
そこを右 横に入って
Take that right!
Get on that street!
何っ
What?!
なんでもいいから
Don't ask questions!
Shit!!
なんだか  よく分からんが
I don't get you at all!
入ったら  即  反転よろしく
As soon as you get past the corner, make a u-turn!
Don't let them get away!
逃がすな
あれっ
Huh?
どっ  どこに行った
W-Where did they go?
その交差点を曲がったんじゃないか
I think they made that turn!
うまくまいてやったぜ
That worked out well.
Hey... transmute it back to something simple.
もっと質素なのに錬成し直せ
なんで  これめちゃくちゃ
Why?!
This looks badass!
カッコイイじゃん
いいから変えろ
Just do it!
頼むから変えろ
Please, just do it!
What the hell?!
んだよ  オレのセンスに
Do you have a problem with my design?!
文句あるってのかよ
ありすぎだ
Too many to list!
またぞろ行き場を失ったな
We have nowhere to go again.
Yeah.
キンブリーの野郎に油断したせいで
I wasted so much time because I let my guard down against Kimblee.
とんだ足止めをくっちまった
アルのヤツ無事にウィンリィたちと
I wonder if Al was able to meet up with Winry and them...
合流できたかな…
Hey, Fullmetal! You listening?
鋼の  聞いてんのか
これからどうする
What do we do now?
Well...
とりあえず
I'd just like some information right now,
whatever that may be.
なんでもいいから  情報が欲しい
アルたちと合流しなくちゃ
We need to meet up with Al and the others.
So where are they?
で  どこにいるんだ
Where do we go to meet up with them?
どこへ行けば  合流できる
アルだったら  どこへ行く
Where would Al go...
考えろ…考えるんだ
Think... Think...!
聞いてる
You listening?
え～っと  その…
Well... so...
父さんが奴隷で賢者の石
You were a slave, and now you're a philosopher's stone?
Yup, exactly.
そう
やっぱり  信じられないか…
Guess it's pretty unbelievable after all...
まあ  分かるよ
Well, I don't blame you.
いきなり  こんなこと言われて
You'd have to be crazy to believe a story like that out of the blue.
納得するヤツは頭がどうかしてる
でも  僕はその
Well... I guess I'm crazy then.
頭がどうかしてるヤツみたいだ
受け入れるの  早いな
You accept things pretty quickly.
To tell you the truth, I'm pretty nervous.
正直  びびってるよ
でも  自分もこんな体だからかな
But... I guess it's easier to believe because my body is also like this.
ねえ 死なないって どんな感じ
Hey... how does it feel to be immortal?
"How does it feel"...?
どうって…
I guess it's convenient in many ways.
この体 いろいろと便利だけど…
大切な人が
But it's sad that I have to see my loved ones go before me.
先に逝ってしまうのが嫌だなぁ
母さん
Mom?
Hey Dad, you're a philosopher's stone,
which means your body isn't exactly normal, right?
ねえ  父さんは賢者の石で
まっとうな体じゃないんでしょ
だったら  僕たちは…
Then are Brother and I...
果たして  まっとうな人間か
Are you asking whether you two are normal humans?
Yeah.
大丈夫だよ
Don't worry.
賢者の石と魂が融合しているけれど
My soul is fused with the philosopher's stone,
核となっているのは
but the actual core that holds me together is myself, a human being.
あくまでオレという人間だから
だが  セントラルにいるあいつ…
But the one at Central...
あれはオレを模した
He's only wearing a shell that resembles me.
皮袋に入っているようなものだ
皮袋
A shell?
Yeah.
So if you break the shell, you should be able to defeat him.
だから  その皮袋を壊せば
あいつを倒せるはずだ
倒す…そうだ
"Defeat"...?
Oh, right.
Aren't they trying to recreate the tragedy at Xerxes by using this country?
あいつら  この国を使って
クセルクセスの再現を
やろうとしてるんじゃないの
すぐにでも止めないと
If we don't stop them soon, there'll be a disaster.
大変なことになるよ
Whoa... not bad.
やるな
ここまで調べたのか
You've figured out this much.
こっちは逆転の錬成陣だな
And this one must be the reverse transmutation circle.
手っとり早いのは
The quick way would be to destroy the underground tunnel.
地下トンネルを壊すことだ
だから ここの地下にある…
That's why-
やめておけ
Don't even think about it.
地下にはプライドという
A powerful homunculus by the name of Pride lurks in the tunnel.
とんでもない人造人間が
待ち構えているぞ
でも  急がないとヤツらの錬成陣が…
But if we don't hurry, their transmutation circle will be...
もう  とっくに完成しているかもしれないな
It may already be complete, or has been for a while.
だったら  なおさら…
Then all the more reason to...!
まだ  その日ではない
"The Day" hasn't come yet.
その日
"The Day"?
アルフォンス
Alphonse.
下ばかり見ないで上を見ろ
Don't be focused on what's at your feet. Look above you.
そうすれば見えてくるものもある
If you do, you'll be able to see new things.
上…
Above...
空  太陽神レト
The sky?
Sun God Leto?
あいつは来るべき日を待っている
He's waiting for "The Day".
なんだよ
What the hell?!
オレが何したってんだよ
What did I  do?!
いいぞ
Good!
元気のいいヤツは大好きだ
Lively people like you make me smile.
地下の番なんて退屈でよ
You have no idea how boring it is to guard this place.
お前みたいなのは大歓迎さ
It's a real pleasure having someone like you visit.
最強の盾…
The Ultimate Shield...!
それにその口調  笑い方…
Along with that tone and the way you laugh...!
くそっ  グリードさんみたいな
Damn you for mimicking Mr. Greed!
まねしやがって
That's right, I'm Greed.
そうだ  オレはグリード
よく知ってるな
Surprised you knew that.
強欲の
The greedy...?
そうさ
Yup.
この世のものすべてオレのもの
This entire world belongs to me.
金も欲しい女も欲しい
I want money, women, status, fame...
地位も名誉も…
この世のすべてが欲しい
"And everything else in this world!"
No way...
そんな…いや  でも…
But it has to be...
Who are you?
お前  何者
Mr. Greed!
グリードさん
Is it really you?!
そうなのか
なんだって  そんな姿…
What happened to you?!
I'm asking who you are!
だから  お前は何者なんだよ
It's me!
オレだよ  ダブリスのビドーだよ
Bido from Dublith!
You forgot your friend?!
仲間の顔  忘れちゃったのかよ
ダブリス  そうかそうか
Dublith!
Ah, it all makes sense now.
Do you remember now?!
思い出した
悪いな  それたぶん
Sorry.
You're probably talking about the previous Greed.
前のグリードだ
Why...
そ…んな…
オレはお前のことを知らねぇ
I don't know you.
グリ…ドさん…
Mr. G...reed...
仲…間…
We're... friends...
侵入者排除がオレの仕事だ
Getting rid of intruders is my job.
Sorry man.
悪いな  ほんと
What's this?
なんだ
You've got to be kidding me...
随分ゲスに成り下がったもんだな  グリード
You've gotten pretty low, Greed.
仲間を手に掛けるとは
Why the hell did you kill your own friend?!
どういう了見だ
He wasn't... my friend...!
仲間じゃ…ねぇ…
じゃあ  この記憶はなんだ
Then what about these memories?!
ビドーとやらが言ってたことも
Are you trying to say that Bido guy was spitting out lies?!
うそっぱちだというのか
前のグリードの記憶だ
They're memories of the previous Greed, not mine!
オレのじゃねぇ
ならば  なぜ  そんなに苦しむ
Then why are you wracked with pain?!
しっかりしろよ  お前
Get your shit together, man!
フラフラしてると
If you start to lose it, my soul will steal back my body!
オレの魂がこの体を取り返しちまうぞ
前のグリードの魂は
The previous Greed's soul had its memories wiped and purified.
記憶を消され浄化された…
過去など  すべて忘れている
I've forgotten all of my past!
My ass you did!
忘れるわけないだろうが
仲間ってのは
Friends are connected by heart!
魂でつながってんだよ
You can't just rinse off something that's stained on your soul!
魂に染みついちまっているものを
すすいで落とすことなんか
できないんだよ
見ろ
Look!
魂が叫んでるじゃないか
Your very being is crying out!
You've cut down a family member that was connected to you by soul!
お前は魂の家族を切って捨てやがった
グリード  すべてを
Greed!
You're supposed to be greedy enough to want to keep everything !
手に入れんとする強欲が
You disgust me!!
聞いてあきれる
The promise we never made
交わしたはずのない約束が
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
今日も
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
僕らの未来を奪おうとする
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
欲しがっていたものを手にしても
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
素直に
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
うまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
あふれる涙は　弱さや後悔じゃない
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
イタミが生んだカケラで
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
どんな瞬間だって運命だって
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
限界だって困難だって
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
あきらめたくないよ
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
このまま離さないで
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
かたく握りしめた　君の右手のぬくもり
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
ここにあるから
Koko ni arukara
これなんかどうかしら
What about this book?
私がちょうど
I read it when I was about your age.
あなたくらいのころに読んだの
世界を旅する冒険家のお話よ
It's a tale about an adventurer who travels around the world.
何
What was that?!
誰
Who is it?
戦いは始まった
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
The battle has begun.
もう誰にも
No one can hold back his anger anymore.
この怒りは止められない
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
生き残るのは己か彼か
Which one of them will survive?
そして  決着の果てに
And what is the truth that is
gradually revealed after the duel?
見えてくる真実とは
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第４５話　『約束の日』
Episode 45, The Promised Day.
集え  志を同じくする者よ
Those who share the same ambition, gather.